lovecamden.org 2019-08-08

# Privacy Policy | Love Camden

****Privacy Policy and Consent Guidance****

The Love Camden website is provided by the London Borough of Camden (“Camden”).

The Data Controller is the London Borough of Camden and we will collect information from you when you register with the Love Camden website and when you provide content. As the Data Controller, Camden is responsible for taking care of the information that you give to us. There are laws in place to make sure that organisations handle data properly: the Data Protection Act 2018 and the EU General Data Protection Regulation.  We’ve referred to these laws as “Data Protection Legislation” in the rest of this document. 

Camden’s Data Protection Officer is called Andrew Maughan and he has overall responsibility for data protection in Camden. If you have any questions or concerns about how your information is being handled at Camden, please do not hesitate to contact his office by writing to the address below, or emailing: [_dpa@camden.gov.uk_](mailto:dpa@camden.gov.uk)

_London Borough of Camden,_  
 _Judd Street_  
 _London_  
 _WC1H 9JE_  
 _020 7974 4444_

If you would like more information about Data Protection, the law and good practice please see the Information Commissioner’s web site who are the statutory governing body for England and Wales [www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/). 

**What is this privacy policy?**

This privacy policy explains how Camden collects, uses and shares your information and the rights that you have over how we deal with it. 

**What information we will collect from you and how we collect it:**

In order to add content to Love Camden we need you to complete a very brief registration form where we ask for your name, telephone number, name of your organisation, your role within that organisation and your email address. You will be asked to create a password to allow you to access your account. We need you to provide your name, the name of your organisation and your role, and your email address and a password in order for you to be able to upload event information to the website. We do not need you to provide a phone number but it may help if we need to contact you. No personal data is displayed on your member's profile, only a user name of your choice.

**How will we use the information that you provide to us (what is the purpose?):**

The information that you provide will be used for the purpose of enabling you to put a listing on the website. We may sometimes need to access your information to assist you in managing your account or your listing. We may sometimes need to use your personal information to contact you about your account or listing. 

Your information will not be shared with anyone else outside of the Council’s Love Camden Team.

**The legal basis for processing your information and how we use it:**

**Consent**

By registering with Love Camden and providing information to appear online, you are consenting to Camden processing your information for the purposes of uploading your content onto the website. You must be over the age of 13 to register with Love Camden and upload content. If you are under the age of 13 we will need consent of a person who has parental responsibility for you. We require a written request from a person who has parental responsibility by emailing lovecamden@camden.gov.uk.

You may withdraw your consent at any time by deleting your profile and account. You can do this by going to [http://www.lovecamden.org/](http://www.lovecamden.org/), clicking on the personal icon in the top right corner of the page, selecting ‘MY ACCOUNT, click ‘EDIT’ and click ‘CANCEL ACCOUNT’ at the bottom of the page. If you do not give your consent or you decide to withdraw your account then Camden will not be able to publish any listings on your behalf on the website. Your account, personal data and any associated listings will be deleted within 24 hours of Camden being notified. 

**Will we share data with anyone else?**

If you subscribe to the newsletter then we will share your data with a third party in order to administer this. You will be given further detail at the point of signing up. We will not share data with anyone else unless required to by law

We will not transfer your Personal Data outside the EU/EEA.

**The criteria used to decide the retention period**

We will keep your details until you choose to delete your account. We will contact you every 3 years to make sure your details are up to date. If you don’t reply, we may delete your account.

**Your Data Subject Rights**

Under data protection law, you have certain rights. These are:

  * the right to request a copy of the information we hold about you;
  * the right to ask us to rectify, erase or restrict processing of your data;
  * the right to ask for data portability;
  * the right to object to automated decision making; and
  * if we are relying on consent, you have the right to withdraw consent at any time. 

There are some exemptions to these rights which means that in certain situations, these rights are not available.  Please see our website [here](https://www.camden.gov.uk/ccm/content/council-and-democracy/general-data-protection-regulation/) and the ICO website [here](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/exemptions/) for more information.  To exercise these rights please use our web form [here](https://www.camden.gov.uk/ccm/content/council-and-democracy/general-data-protection-regulation/)

**Automated decision Making and Profiling.**

We are not using automated Decision Making or profiling to process your Personal Data.

For further information on how Camden deals with personal information across the Council, please see the Corporate Privacy Policy: [www.camden.gov.uk//privacystatement](http://www.camden.gov.uk/privacystatement)

****Mailing list****

When you visit Love Camden, you have the option of signing up to our newsletter. If you consent to this, you are agreeing to allow Love Camden to send you the Love Camden newsletter. By subscribing to the newsletter, you agree to us providing your name and email  address to Granicus for the sole purpose of providing the newsletter service to you. You may opt out and withdraw your consent at any time by clicking the on the subscriber preferences link at the bottom of the email. You can subscribe to the mailing list [here](https://public.govdelivery.com/accounts/UKLBC/subscriber/new?preferences=true). If you withdraw your consent then Camden will be unable to provide the newsletter to you. You can read the privacy policy for Granicus [here](https://granicus.com/privacy-policy/) and also when you sign up.

****Cookies - Collecting information automatically****

We collect statistics about your visit to our website. We use this information to track user activity which in turn helps us to improve the website. These statistics do not contain personal data and cannot be traced back to an individual. We use ‘cookies’ to collect this statistical information. However, the cookies themselves do not store personal information. You can view our cookies policy [here](https://www.camden.gov.uk/ccm/content/council-and-democracy/about-the-council/about-this-site/disclaimer-and-privacy-statement/?page=5#section-5)

**The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority:**

_You can complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office if you are unhappy with how the council has handled your personal data.   It would be helpful if you contacted us first at _[_dpa@camden.gov.uk_](mailto:dpa@camden.gov.uk) _to see if we can resolve the problem.   You can contact the ICO at __casework@ico.org.uk_ _  __telephone   0303 123 1113, or post to Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, S9 5AF. _[_www.ico.org.uk_](http://www.ico.org.uk/) __

For further information on how Camden deals with personal information across the Council, please see the Corporate Privacy Policy: [www.camden.gov.uk//privacystatement](http://www.camden.gov.uk/privacystatement)

Camden will systematically review this statement.
